<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xml:base="https://2010.fossasia.org"  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
 <title>FOSSASIA</title>
 <link>https://2010.fossasia.org</link>
 <description></description>
 <language>en</language>
<item>
 <title>FOSSASIA 2010: Bridge to Asia</title>
 <link>https://2010.fossasia.org/fossasia-2010-bridge-asia</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/sites/default/files/fossasia-2010-group-foto-contributors.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;351&quot; width=&quot;640&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://fossasia.org&quot;&gt;FOSSASIA&lt;/a&gt; 2010 took place at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.raffles-international-college-hcm.edu.vn&quot;&gt;Raffles College&lt;/a&gt; campus in Ho Chi Minh City (Saigon), Vietnam from November 12th to  14th. This inaugural event brought together over 350 international and  local developers and users in 62 presentations and panels. An amazing  crowd of 90 enthusiastic volunteers supported participants. FOSSASIA  attendees came from 30 countries including Cambodia, Singapore,  Indonesia, Japan, India, Taiwan, Malaysia, Germany, France, England,  Australia, and the US.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The goal of FOSSASIA is to provide  knowledge of free and open source software and to offer the community a  place to meet and share ideas. The annual conference brings together  members of the Asian FOSS community along with the international  community, thus fostering cooperation across projects and across  borders. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Special Tracks: Women in IT and Lightweight Computing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The 2010 event offered 5 tracks including the two special theme tracks &quot;Women in IT&quot; and &quot;Lightweight Computing&quot;. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Hong Phuc Dang from &lt;a href=&quot;http://mbm.vn&quot;&gt;MBM&lt;/a&gt; Vietnam said of the Women in IT panel:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;&quot;It  is fascinating to see so many girls participating. I am very happy that  we have chosen &#039;Women in IT&#039; as a theme as it attracted many students  to join us.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Other participants of the women panel were Lilly Nguyen (UCLA, US), Van Thi Bich Ty (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pcworld.com.vn&quot;&gt;PCWorld, Vietnam&lt;/a&gt;), Mary Agnes James (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.seacem.com&quot;&gt;Seacem&lt;/a&gt;), &lt;a href=&quot;http://chenglita.wordpress.com&quot;&gt;Lita Cheng&lt;/a&gt; (Community Cambodia) and &lt;a href=&quot;http://blueladyblog.com&quot;&gt;Kounila Keo&lt;/a&gt; (ICT4D Cambodia).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;The  heated debate during the panel definitely portrayed some of the issues  and challenges young female developers face. I hope that it made many of  the younger women more interested in participating in the community. I  am excited to see more involvement of women in IT in Asia in the near  future&quot; said &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.deuxlits.com&quot;&gt;Lilly Nguyen &lt;/a&gt;from the US.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/sites/default/files/women-panel-fossasia-2010-Hong-Phuc-Dang-middle-and-Lilly-Nguyen-right.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; width=&quot;640&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &quot;Lightweight Computing&quot; track also generated a lot of interest. &lt;a href=&quot;http://lubuntu.net&quot;&gt;Lubuntu, the lightweight version of Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt;, attracted the attention of local developers. Additionally, mobile solutions such as &lt;a href=&quot;http://android.com&quot;&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://xpud.org&quot;&gt;Xpad/Xpud&lt;/a&gt; were covered in several presentations by &lt;a href=&quot;http://penkia.net&quot;&gt;Ping-Hsun Chen&lt;/a&gt; (Taiwan), Pham Huu Ngon (Vietnam) and Tan Quang Sang (Vietnam).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/sites/default/files/cambodia-vietnamese-malaysian-participants-fossasia-2010.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OpenOffice.org Asia Meet Up&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;FOSSASIA was particularly happy to welcome the &lt;a href=&quot;http://openoffice.org&quot;&gt;OpenOffice.org&lt;/a&gt; community who sponsored the event. As head of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://openoffice.vn&quot;&gt;Vietnamese OOo localization team&lt;/a&gt;, Vu Do Quynh from &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.hanoilug.org/&quot;&gt;Hanoilug&lt;/a&gt; presented on the various ways that people could contribute to the OOo community while &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gniibe.org/log/&quot;&gt;Yutaka Niibe&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.netfort.gr.jp/%7Eyabuki/&quot;&gt;Yukiharu Yabuki&lt;/a&gt; presented on OOo&#039;s use by the Japenese government in the Osaka Prefecture.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mini-Debconf, Fedora Release Party and Mozilla&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;FOSSASIA 2010 was also an opportunity for the Debian community to organize a &lt;a href=&quot;http://debian.org&quot;&gt;Mini-Debconf&lt;/a&gt;. Debian &lt;a href=&quot;http://wiki.debian.org/DebianVietnam/MiniDebConf2010&quot;&gt;developers present&lt;/a&gt; included among others &lt;a href=&quot;http://dr.jones.dk&quot;&gt;Jonas Smedegaard&lt;/a&gt; (Denmark), &lt;a href=&quot;http://wiki.debian.org/PaulWise&quot;&gt;Paul Wise&lt;/a&gt; (Australia) and &lt;a href=&quot;http://thomas.goirand.fr&quot;&gt;Thomas Goirand &lt;/a&gt;(France/China).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/sites/default/files/Debconf-Participants_Yukiharu-YABUKI-and-Arne-Goetje.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;423&quot; width=&quot;640&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To celebrate the release of &lt;a href=&quot;http://fedoraproject.org&quot;&gt;Fedora&lt;/a&gt; 14, Ambassador &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.iwayvietnam.com/tuanta/&quot;&gt;Anh Tuan Truong&lt;/a&gt; (Vietnam) and &lt;a href=&quot;http://pierros.papadeas.gr/?p=186&quot;&gt;Pierros Papadeas&lt;/a&gt; (Greece) hosted the world&#039;s largest release party. The even took place  at the Ho Chi Minh City University of Pedagogy. Pierros--an active  Mozilla contributor---had&amp;nbsp; this to say about the release event:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;&quot;It  was AWESOME. At first I thought most of them were there due to their  teachers, but&amp;nbsp; when we started a Q&amp;amp;A session I realized I was so  wrong… they were&amp;nbsp; asking about PAE kernels, broadcom drivers, dual boot  and LVM etc! By the end of the party we gave out T-shirts, LiveCDs and  stickers to everyone, all 134 people where there! I believe that sets a  new fedora record! The local Vietnamese community was introduced and  many people are already starting to send emails wanting to start  translating.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/sites/default/files/fedora-release-party.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;345&quot; width=&quot;640&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The FOSS Bridge to Asia&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Projects also used the event as an opportunity to showcase new tools and devices like the &lt;a href=&quot;http://fdmbx.net&quot;&gt;Freedombox&lt;/a&gt; project of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://freifunk.net&quot;&gt;Freifunk&lt;/a&gt; community and the latest version of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://crypto-stick.org&quot;&gt;Crypto-Stick&lt;/a&gt;. Jan Suhr (Germany/Singapore) showed the device as a combination of both open hardware and open software.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the web track, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bytebot.net&quot;&gt;Colin Charles&lt;/a&gt; (Malaysia) presented the newest improvements of &lt;a href=&quot;http://mariadb.org&quot;&gt;MariaDB&lt;/a&gt;. In addition, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aidiq.com/blog/michael-howden&quot;&gt;Michael Howden&lt;/a&gt; (New Zealand) conducted a workshop for &lt;a href=&quot;http://sahanafoundation.org&quot;&gt;Sahane Eden&lt;/a&gt;,  a platform to provide support in the case of disasters. The workshop  gave students a chance understand the information needs of disaster  scenarios and they were able to contribute to the localization of the  software.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Several web content management systems set-up information booths at the event. These included: &lt;a href=&quot;http://typo3.org&quot;&gt;TYPO3&lt;/a&gt; with a booth organized by Dominik Stankowski from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.web-essentials.asia&quot;&gt;Web Essentials&lt;/a&gt; Cambodia and &lt;a href=&quot;http://drupal.org&quot;&gt;Drupal&lt;/a&gt; (Virak Hor, Cambodia and Quang Thong Tran, Vietnam). The event also introduced other tools such as &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zabbix.com&quot;&gt;Zabbix&lt;/a&gt;, a monitoring software (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.walterheck.com&quot;&gt;Walter Heck&lt;/a&gt;, Netherlands). One more hot topic was the enterprise p2p search engine &lt;a href=&quot;http://yacy.net&quot;&gt;YaCy.net&lt;/a&gt; of Michael Christen (Germany). A number of more established projects  had the opportunity to share their news at the event including the  desktop environments &lt;a href=&quot;http://kde.org&quot;&gt;KDE&lt;/a&gt; with a presentation about Qt (Gregory Schlomoff, France), &lt;a href=&quot;http://gnome.org&quot;&gt;GNOME&lt;/a&gt; (Kien Truc Le, Vietnam), and &lt;a href=&quot;http://lxde.org&quot;&gt;LXDE&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;http://nguyentieuhau.wordpress.com&quot;&gt;Duy Hung Tran&lt;/a&gt;, Vietnam).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/sites/default/files/audience-at-fossasia-2010.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;359&quot; width=&quot;640&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unconference&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Taking a cue from previous &lt;a href=&quot;http://barcamp.vn&quot;&gt;barcamps&lt;/a&gt; and &#039;unconferences,&#039; many attendees presented lightning talks. &lt;a href=&quot;http://preetam.net&quot;&gt;Preetam Rai&lt;/a&gt;, an Android App inventor, shared photos and tales about other barcamps throughout Southeast Asia. Mary Agnes James from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.seacem.com&quot;&gt;Seacem&lt;/a&gt; spoke about todays chances to connect and share with e-media and social networks. Seacem also graciously sponsored this event.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Libre Graphics and Open Design&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;During the final day of the event, FOSSASIA held it&#039;s first &lt;a href=&quot;http://libregraphicsmeeting.org&quot;&gt;Libre Graphics Day&lt;/a&gt;.  Arne Goetje (Germany/Taiwan) introduced his new approach for a  pan-Asian fonts library. Jon Philips (US) from Status.net and Dave  Crossland (UK) from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/webfonts&quot;&gt;Google Fonts project&lt;/a&gt; conducted an Open Design Workshop. The workshops brought curious crowds and has ultimately seeded plans for the &lt;a href=&quot;http://opendesign.asia&quot;&gt;Open Design Weeks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/sites/default/files/Libre-Graphics-Jon-Phillips-Participants-fossasia2010.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;411&quot; width=&quot;640&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;See you in Vietnam&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thanks  again to the amazing crowd at FOSSASIA - developers, translators, event  organizers, bloggers, teachers, students, designers and lost but not  least our enthusiastic volunteers! See you all in 2011!&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;* &lt;a href=&quot;http://fossasia.org&quot;&gt;FOSSASIA&lt;/a&gt; 2011 will take place in Ho Chi Minh City (Saigon) on November 11-12&lt;br&gt;* The &lt;a href=&quot;http://opendesign.asia&quot;&gt;Open Design Weeks&lt;/a&gt; will be celebrated from in Ho Chi Minh City and Can Tho in the Mekong Delta.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/sites/default/files/pierros-papadeas-with-fossasia-participants.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;409&quot; width=&quot;640&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Links:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;* FOSSASIA &lt;a href=&quot;http://fossasia.org&quot; title=&quot;http://fossasia.org&quot;&gt;http://fossasia.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;* Open Design Weeks Asia, &lt;a href=&quot;http://opendesign.asia&quot; title=&quot;http://opendesign.asia&quot;&gt;http://opendesign.asia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--break--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
 <pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2010 18:49:08 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Hong Phuc</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">274 at https://2010.fossasia.org</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Schedule</title>
 <link>https://2010.fossasia.org/schedule</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;The main topics of FOSSASIA  2010 are &lt;strong&gt;Lightweight Computing&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Women in IT&lt;/strong&gt;. We also have sessions dedicated to &lt;strong&gt;OpenOffice.org&lt;/strong&gt; and will host a Debian &lt;strong&gt;Mini-Debconf&lt;/strong&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;zeroBorder&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; cellpadding=&quot;4&quot; width=&quot;597&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=&quot;#ffffcc&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day&lt;br&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=&quot;#ffffcc&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time&lt;br&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=&quot;#ffffcc&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Event&lt;br&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=&quot;#ffffcc&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday, Nov. 11&lt;br&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;20.00&lt;br&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Pre-Meeting&lt;br&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Spotted Cow Bar111 Bui Vien, dist 1. HCMC(opposite to Happy Inn, closed to Pham Ngu Lao &amp;amp; De Tham) &lt;a href=&quot;http://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;amp;source=s_q&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;geocode=&amp;amp;q=111+Bui+Vien,+Ho+Chi+Minh+City,+Vietnam&amp;amp;sll=37.0625,-95.677068&amp;amp;sspn=27.284961,56.513672&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;hq=&amp;amp;hnear=111+Bui+Vien,+ph%C6%B0%E1%BB%9Dng+Ph%E1%BA%A1m+Ng%C5%A9+L%C3%A3o,+District+1,+Ho+Chi+Minh+City,+Vietnam&amp;amp;ll=10.765331,106.686237&amp;amp;spn=0.008242,0.021973&amp;amp;z=16&quot;&gt;Google Maps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=&quot;#ccccff&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday, Nov. 12&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=&quot;#ccccff&quot;&gt;9.00-16.00&lt;br&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=&quot;#ccccff&quot;&gt;Info Day (15-20 min presentations about projects and set up of info tables)&lt;br&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=&quot;#ccccff&quot;&gt;Raffles Institute (Theatre Hall)&lt;br&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=&quot;#ccccff&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=&quot;#ccccff&quot;&gt;Evening&lt;br&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=&quot;#ccccff&quot;&gt;Hack Sessions&lt;br&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=&quot;#ccccff&quot;&gt;City Cafe or Hack Office of Qhoach.com to be decided adhoc&lt;br&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Saturday, Nov.13&lt;br&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;9.00-17.15&lt;br&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Community Day (keynotes, talks, workshops)&lt;br&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Raffles Institute (Theatre Hall and 5 Rooms)&lt;br&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Evening&lt;br&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Social Meet Up&lt;br&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Location in the city to be announced&lt;br&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=&quot;#ccccff&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sunday, Nov. 14&lt;br&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=&quot;#ccccff&quot;&gt;9.00-15.30&lt;br&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=&quot;#ccccff&quot;&gt;Workshops and Follow ups&lt;br&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=&quot;#ccccff&quot;&gt;Raffles Institute (5 Workshop Rooms)&lt;br&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monday, Nov. 15&lt;br&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;8.00&lt;br&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Mekong Excursion organized by tour company&lt;br&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Mekong Delta&lt;br&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=&quot;#ccccff&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monday-Friday&lt;br&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=&quot;#ccccff&quot;&gt;To be decided&lt;br&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=&quot;#ccccff&quot;&gt;Presentations and Meetings with students and professors in universities&lt;br&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=&quot;#ccccff&quot;&gt;Locations in Ho Chi Minh City&lt;br&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--break--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FOSSASIA 2010 Tracks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;a) Lightweight solutions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Lightweight solutions are currently a strong focus in all major IT markets be it&lt;br&gt; * in the mobile device sector with solutions like Android, MeeGo, Chrome OS, Symbian, Bada, OpenWrt and embedded Debian&lt;br&gt; * in the desktop market with lightweight trends with KDE, GNOME, LXDE  and XFCE in Ubuntu and derivates like lubuntu, lightweights spins of  Fedora, OpenSuse and others&lt;br&gt; * in the web/browser market offering lighter and standard compliant solutions with HTML5&lt;br&gt; * or in the server and cloud market with the trend to lighter NoSQL solutions which are more suitable for large data structures&lt;br&gt; * and in the emerging Open Hardware sector&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;b) Fostering the Asian community and Women in IT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;While  most Open Source and Free Software projects are based in Western  countries there is an increasing number of projects from Asia. One very  successful project with a strong Asian community is LXDE, which is a  community partner of FOSSASIA. Nevertheless, the number of Asian  developers in Open Source is still limited even though the largest part  of the human population lives in Asia. Women are also underrepresented  in the IT community. The FOSSASIA team strongly encourages the  participation of young women and achieved this goal with an astounding  participation of women in 2009 – more than half of all attendees. The  2010 event will continue to support women to become contributors and  learn about using Open Source and Free Software with offering additional  track space for:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;*  Linux workshops for women&lt;br&gt; * Design workshops with open tools like GIMP and Inkscape&lt;br&gt; * A womens panel on how to collaborate across genders and cultures&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;c) OpenOffice.org and Open Document Formats Key Focus&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;d) Debian Mini-Debconf Asia&lt;/strong&gt; (Debian Wiki page: &lt;a href=&quot;http://wiki.debian.org/DebianVietnam/MiniDebConf2010&quot; title=&quot;http://wiki.debian.org/DebianVietnam/MiniDebConf2010&quot;&gt;http://wiki.debian.org/DebianVietnam/MiniDebConf2010&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;Tracks&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;We plan to have up to 4 sessions in parallel with approximately 65 talks and workshops in total for FOSSASIA 2010.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Based on our vision of fostering “Lightweight Computing and Women in IT”, FOSSASIA 2010 will cover the following topics:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; cellpadding=&quot;4&quot; width=&quot;597&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td width=&quot;158&quot; bgcolor=&quot;#ffffcc&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: x-small;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Track&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td width=&quot;423&quot; bgcolor=&quot;#ffffcc&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: x-small;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Topics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt; &lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td width=&quot;158&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: x-small;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Track 1: Lightweight Technologies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td width=&quot;423&quot;&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: x-small;&quot;&gt;Lightweight desktop technologies and coding&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: x-small;&quot;&gt;HTML5 and the Web Technologies &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: x-small;&quot;&gt;OSS  &amp;amp; Mobile Devices , platform for Mobile devices (Android, Chrome OS,  Maemo, Symbian, Moblin, Bada) and software solution for Tablets /  Smartbook s&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: x-small;&quot;&gt;Handling larger data structures with lighter “Not only SQL”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt; &lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td width=&quot;158&quot; bgcolor=&quot;#ccccff&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: x-small;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Track 2: Growing the community, expanding Openness&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td width=&quot;423&quot; bgcolor=&quot;#ccccff&quot;&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: x-small;&quot;&gt;Open source hardware (Thin clients, Routers,Mini-Computers)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: x-small;&quot;&gt;Libre Graphics, Creative Commons&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: x-small;&quot;&gt;Free culture communities &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt; &lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td width=&quot;158&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: x-small;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Track 3: OpenOffice.org/ODF&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td width=&quot;423&quot;&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: x-small;&quot;&gt;OpenOffice.org, Open Document Format and the future of Office&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt; &lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td width=&quot;158&quot; bgcolor=&quot;#ccccff&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: x-small;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Track 4: Debconf&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td width=&quot;423&quot; bgcolor=&quot;#ccccff&quot;&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: x-small;&quot;&gt;Debian Conference, Mini-Debconf Asia&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description>
 <pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2010 03:22:25 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Hong Phuc</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">7 at https://2010.fossasia.org</guid>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
